pharmer.org 2011-11-26

# Privacy Statement | Pharmer.org

Submitted by davidm on April 24, 2005 - 8:49pm

**_Privacy Statement Last Updated 04-07-09_**

This Privacy Statement describes our current privacy practices with regard to information we collect when you or your computer interact with [ Pharmer.org](http://www.pharmer.org/). 

**Information Collection and Use**  
The only information we collect from our users is a valid email address which is required to create an account. Your email address will **never** intentionally be divulged to third parties without your permission and consent. We despise spam as much as you do.

**Log Files**  
We use the information in our server log files to analyze trends in the usage of our website, to administer and maintain our website, to track a user's path through our website, and to gather broad demographic statistics about our website and the ways in which the site is used. Most of the information in these files is not unique to you as an individual, such as the files requested and pages you visit on our website, the websites from which you may have been referred to our website, and information about the type of browser you use and its settings. Some of the log files contain IP addresses and other personally identifiable information, which are used to identify user connections and to resolve technical issues related to administration of our website.

**Cookies**  
A cookie is a small text file stored on a computer that contains information associated with that computer. Our website uses cookies for several purposes, such as maintaining your login state, customizing the content of our web pages, and improving the security of your use of our website.

**Web Beacons**  
We also use third party advertisements on Pharmer.org to support our site.  Some of these advertisers may use technology such as cookies and web beacons when they advertise on our site, which will also send these advertisers (such as Google through the Google AdSense program) information including your IP address, your ISP , the browser you used to visit our site, and in some cases, whether you have Flash installed.  This is generally used for geotargeting purposes (showing New York real estate ads to someone in New York, for example) or showing certain ads based on specific sites visited (such as showing cooking ads to someone who frequents cooking sites).

**DoubleClick DART cookies**  
We also may use DART cookies for ad serving through Google’s DoubleClick, which places a cookie on your computer when you are browsing the web and visit a site using DoubleClick advertising (including some Google AdSense advertisements).  This cookie is used to serve ads specific to you and your interests (”interest based targeting”).  The ads served will be targeted based on your previous browsing history (For example, if you have been viewing sites about visiting Las Vegas, you may see Las Vegas hotel advertisements when viewing a non-related site, such as on a site about hockey).  DART uses “non personally identifiable information”.  It does NOT track personal information about you, such as your name, email address, physical address, telephone number, social security numbers, bank account numbers or credit card numbers.  You can opt-out of this ad serving on all sites using this advertising by visiting [DoubleClick](http://doubleclick.com/privacy/dart_adserving.aspx)

  You can choose to disable or selectively turn off our cookies or third-party cookies in your browser settings, or by managing preferences in programs such as Norton Internet Security.  However, this can affect how you are able to interact with our site as well as other websites.  This could include the inability to login to services or programs, such as logging into forums or accounts.

Deleting cookies does not mean you are permanently opted out of any advertising program.  Unless you have settings that disallow cookies, the next time you visit a site running the advertisements, a new cookie will be added.

**Public Forums**  
You may participate in public forums on our website. Any information you make available in these forums, such as an email address, would become public information and could be used by others to send you unsolicited communications. Please be careful about disclosing personal information in public forums.

**Changes to this Privacy Statement**  
[ Pharmer.org](http://www.pharmer.org/) will occasionally update this Privacy Statement as our website evolves. When we do, we will also revise the "last updated" date at the top of the Privacy Statement. Sections of our updated Privacy Statement are based on the AdSense Privacy Policy provided by [JenSense](http://www.jensense.com/)

**Contact Us**  
If you have questions about this Privacy Statement, its implementation, or our practices, please contact us at admin@pharmer.org.
